<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Amazon Lightsail Workshop on Scaling and Deploying Applications with Amazon Lightsail</title>
    <link>http://lightsailworkshop.com/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Amazon Lightsail Workshop on Scaling and Deploying Applications with Amazon Lightsail</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    
	<atom:link href="http://lightsailworkshop.com/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>2.1 - Deploy MongoDB</title>
      <link>http://lightsailworkshop.com/mean/lab2/create_mongo.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://lightsailworkshop.com/mean/lab2/create_mongo.html</guid>
      <description>In this section you will deploy a standalone MongoDB instance. To start you will create an Ubuntu Linux instance using an OS Only blueprint. As part of the instance creation process you&amp;rsquo;ll supply a launch script that will install MongoDB.
 From the Lightsail console home page click Create Instance
 Make sure Linux/Unix is selected under Select a platform and then under Select a blueprint click OS Only and choose Ubuntu</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>1.1 - Build the LAMP instance</title>
      <link>http://lightsailworkshop.com/lamp/lab1/build_instance.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://lightsailworkshop.com/lamp/lab1/build_instance.html</guid>
      <description>The first step in deploying the Todo application is creating a LAMP stack instance in Lightsail.
 From the Lightsail console home page click Create Instance
 Choose the region you want to deploy your instance in to. Under Instance Location click Change AWS Region and Availability Zone and select the appropriate region.
 Make sure that Linux/Unix is selected under Select a platform, and then under Blueprint choose LAMP</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>1.1 - Build the MEAN instance</title>
      <link>http://lightsailworkshop.com/mean/lab1/build_instance.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://lightsailworkshop.com/mean/lab1/build_instance.html</guid>
      <description>The first step in deploying the Todo application is creating a MEAN stack instance in Lightsail. When creating the instance, you will supply a Lightsail launch script to actually install the application.
 From the Lightsail console home page click Create Instance
 Make sure that Linux/Unix is selected under Select a platform, and then under Blueprint choose MEAN
 Click +Add Launch Script
 Paste the script below into the text box</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>3.1 - Reconfigure MySQL</title>
      <link>http://lightsailworkshop.com/lamp/lab3/reconfigure_mysql.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://lightsailworkshop.com/lamp/lab3/reconfigure_mysql.html</guid>
      <description>Export Environment Variables using the values from your Lightrsail Database intance. In the case of the image below the variables would be configured as follows
ENDPOINT=&amp;lt;&amp;gt; USERNAME= PASSWORD=  Check to make sure the envrionment variables are set correctly:
echo $ENDPOINT &amp;amp;&amp;amp; echo $USERNAME &amp;amp;&amp;amp; echo $PASSWORD  Create a new configuration file that points to the Lightsail database:
cat /opt/bitnami/apache2/configs/config.php.bak | \ sed &amp;quot;s/&amp;lt;endpoint&amp;gt;/$ENDPOINT/; \ s/&amp;lt;username&amp;gt;/$USERNAME/; \ s/&amp;lt;password&amp;gt;/$PASSWORD/;&amp;quot; \ &amp;gt;&amp;gt; /opt/bitnami/apache2/configs/config.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>1.2 - Configure MongoDB</title>
      <link>http://lightsailworkshop.com/mean/lab1/configure_mongo.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://lightsailworkshop.com/mean/lab1/configure_mongo.html</guid>
      <description>In this section you are going to configure the Mongo database for use with the application. Specifically you are going to add a username and password (tasks for both) for the application database (also called tasks). You&amp;rsquo;ll do all this using the Mongo client from the Lightsail command line.
The following steps are performed from the MEAN instance command line using either your own SSH client or Lightsail&amp;rsquo;s web-based SSH access.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>2.1 - Deploy the Application</title>
      <link>http://lightsailworkshop.com/lamp/lab2/deploy_app.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://lightsailworkshop.com/lamp/lab2/deploy_app.html</guid>
      <description>In this section we are going to deploy the application code into our lightsail instance, as well as configure the connection between the PHP applicaiton and the locally-running MySQL database.
{{% notice tip %}} The following steps are performed from the LAMP instance command line using either your own SSH client or Lightsail&amp;rsquo;s web-based SSH access. {{% /notice %}}
 Ensure you are SSH&amp;rsquo;d into your LAMP instance,
 The LAMP Bitnami image has some default web pages installed, you will need to remove those so you can deploy the PHP application.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>2.2 - Deploy the front-end</title>
      <link>http://lightsailworkshop.com/mean/lab2/create_fe.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://lightsailworkshop.com/mean/lab2/create_fe.html</guid>
      <description>Next you are going to create the web front end instance. To build the front end instance you will start with the Lightsail Node.js blueprint and add in the application code from GitHub. Additionally the isntance will use a process manager, PM2, to ensure that our application starts up automatically.
Check out the website to learn more about PM2.
 From the Lightsail console home page click Create Instance
 Make sure Linux/Unix is selected under Select a platform and then under Select a blueprint choose Node.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>1.2 - Deploy the database</title>
      <link>http://lightsailworkshop.com/lamp/lab1/deploy_database.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://lightsailworkshop.com/lamp/lab1/deploy_database.html</guid>
      <description>In this section we&amp;rsquo;ll deploy a Lightsail database. Lightsail databases are a managed database service that allow you to get away from the complexity of deploying and managing database software. Lightsail manages the underlying infrastructure and database engine, you only need to worry about creating and deploying the actual databases and tables running inside the service.
 From the Lightsail console home page select Databases from the horizontal menu
 Click Create database</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>1.3 - Start and test the app</title>
      <link>http://lightsailworkshop.com/mean/lab1/deploy_app.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://lightsailworkshop.com/mean/lab1/deploy_app.html</guid>
      <description>1.3 - Start and test our application Now that the application is installed and the database configured it is ready to be started.
The following steps are performed from the MEAN instance command line using either your own SSH client or Lightsail&amp;rsquo;s web-based SSH access.
  Change into the application directory
cd ~/todo  Start the application by executing the following command
sudo DEBUG=app:* ./bin/www  You should see a message such as:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>2.3 - Scale the front-end</title>
      <link>http://lightsailworkshop.com/mean/lab2/snapshots.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://lightsailworkshop.com/mean/lab2/snapshots.html</guid>
      <description>Return to the Lightsail console home page
 Click the 3 dot menu for the node-fe-1 instance and choose Manage
 From the horizontal menu choose Snapshots
 Click Create Snapshot
Under Recent snapshots the status will change to creating, you will need to wait for the process to complete to move forward. This can take up to 5 minutes.
 Click the 3 dot menu to the right of the newly created snapshot and select Create new instance</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>4.1 - Scale the front-end</title>
      <link>http://lightsailworkshop.com/lamp/lab4/snapshots.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://lightsailworkshop.com/lamp/lab4/snapshots.html</guid>
      <description>Return to the Lightsail console home page
 Click the 3 dot menu for the PHP-fe-1 instance and choose Manage
 From the horizontal menu choose Snapshots
 Click Create Snapshot
  Under Recent snapshots the status will change to creating, you will need to wait for the process to complete to move forward. This can take up to 5 minutes.
  Click the 3 dot menu to the right of the newly created snapshot and select Create new instance</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>1.3 - Create the load balancer</title>
      <link>http://lightsailworkshop.com/lamp/lab1/create_lb.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://lightsailworkshop.com/lamp/lab1/create_lb.html</guid>
      <description> Return to the Lightsail console home page and choose Networking from the horizontal menu.
 Click Create Load Balancer
  Make sure you&amp;rsquo;re deploying your load balancer into the same region that you deployed your LAMP instance and database into.
  Scroll down and enter todo-lb for the load balancer name
 Click Create Load Balancer
  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>2.4 - Load balance the front-end</title>
      <link>http://lightsailworkshop.com/mean/lab2/load_balancer.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://lightsailworkshop.com/mean/lab2/load_balancer.html</guid>
      <description>Return to the Lightsail console home page and choose Networking from the horizontal menu.
 Click Create Load Balancer
 Scroll down and enter todo-lb for the load balancer name
 Click Create Load Balancer
 Under Target instances choose node-fe-1 from the dropdown list
 Click Attach
 Click Attach another and repeat the previous two steps for node-fe-2 and node-fe-3
  It will take several minutes for all three instances to register their health checks as Passed once this has happened, move to the next step</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>4.2 - Load balance the front-end</title>
      <link>http://lightsailworkshop.com/lamp/lab4/load_balancer.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://lightsailworkshop.com/lamp/lab4/load_balancer.html</guid>
      <description>Return to the Lightsail console home page and choose Networking from the horizontal menu and click on the name of your previously-created load balancer.
 Under Target instances choose PHP-fe-1 from the dropdown list
 Click Attach
 Click Attach another and repeat the previous two steps for PHP-fe-2 and PHP-fe-3
  It will take several minutes for all three instances to register their health checks as Passed once this has happened, move to the next step</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>